<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psykiatri on Loggen</title>
    <link>/tags/psykiatri/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psykiatri on Loggen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/psykiatri/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fungerar psykofarmaka?</title>
      <link>/post/psychopharma_efficacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/psychopharma_efficacy/</guid>
      <description>true  Bloggar Blogg
 Reviderade resultat från kliniska prövningar BMJ Editorial: Liberating the data from clinical trials
Prövning N Ursprungligt resultat:
Reviderat resultat
Reviderad analys: Restoring Study 329: efficacy and harms of paroxetine and imipramine in treatment of major depression in adolescence
  Övrigt All Trials Registered, All Results Reported är ett initiativ från Ben Goldacre, BMJ, Centre for Evidence-based Medicine, Cochrane Collaboration, James Lind Initiative, PLOS and Sense about Science and is being led in the US by Sense About Science USA, Dartmouth’s Geisel School of Medicine and the Dartmouth Institute for Health Policy &amp;amp; Clinical Practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poddar om psykologi, psykiatri och kognition</title>
      <link>/post/podcasts_cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/podcasts_cognition/</guid>
      <description>Hidden brain Hidden Brain’s host Shankar Vedantam reveals the unconscious patterns that drive human behavior, the biases that shape our choices, and the triggers that direct the course of our relationships.
Länk: https://www.npr.org/podcasts/510308/hidden-brain
Rekommenderade episoder: I’m Right, You’re Wrong, Radio Replay: Loving the Lie . Radio Replay: Crime As A Disease.
 Oxford psychiatry podcast These podcasts provide an introduction to core topics in psychiatry, and to research undertaken in the Oxford University Department of Psychiatry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psykiatriresurser</title>
      <link>/post/psychiatryresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/psychiatryresources/</guid>
      <description>tru  Bloggar Carlat Psychiatry Blog är ganska inaktiv, men det kan finnas en del äldre material samt länkar av intresse?
Mind Hacks skriver om forskningsprocessen med mera.
Neurosceptic
Shrink Rap är en blogg av och för psykiatriker.
Real Psychiatry och tekniska noter om psykiatrisk behandling från samma författare.
1 Boring Old Man är inaktiv (författaren avliden).
Amazing World of Psychiatry verkar innehålla en del intressant om psykiatrihistoria, antropologi och psykiatrisk forskning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vansinnet i historia och litteratur</title>
      <link>/post/madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/madness/</guid>
      <description>Övrigt Dan Carlins podcast om religiöst vansinne i den Tyska staden Mûnster under 1500-talet:
 Murderous milennial preachers and prophets take over the German city of Munster after Martin Luther unleashes a Pandora’s Box of religious anarchy with the Protestant Revolution.
 Länk: Prophets of Doom
Distanskursen “Narrating madness” vid Umeå Universitet:
 While locating texts within their contemporary contexts as far as religion, gender and medicine, the course will engage with significant modern theoretical discussions of madness and creativity as offered by Foucault, Freud and others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>